<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mdoc title="Introduction" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">

  <msection id="introduction" title="Introduction">
  
    <p>The <i>svnant</i> project provides a set of <a href="http://ant.apache.org">Ant</a> extensions
    which can be used to interact with <a href="http://subversion.apache.org">Subversion</a> 
    repositories.</p>
  
  </msection>
  
  <msection id="setup" title="Setup">
  
    <p>As with most Ant extensions, SvnAnt's task and type names must be 
    <a href="http://ant.apache.org/manual/CoreTasks/typedef.html">mapped to their 
    implementing classes</a> before being used in an Ant build file. An example of how to use 
    the <em>antlib</em> bundled in SvnAnt's JAR file to perform that registration follows:</p>
    
    <snippet type="xml" id="snippetbasicdeclaration">
    
      &lt;path id="path.svnant"&gt;
          &lt;pathelement location="${basedir}/svnant.jar"/&gt;
          &lt;pathelement location="${basedir}/svnClientAdapter.jar"/&gt;
          &lt;!-- ... --&gt;
      &lt;/path&gt;
    
      &lt;typedef 
          resource="org/tigris/subversion/svnant/svnantlib.xml" 
          classpathref="path.svnant"
      /&gt;
      
    </snippet>
  
    <remark>Please be aware that the previously used declaration mechanism using the file
    <code>svnant.properties</code> is no longer supported so it's necessary to update
    your declaration if necessary.</remark>
  
    <msubsection id="binding" title="Binding">

      <p>The path declaration shown <a href="#snippetbasicdeclaration">above</a> only contains the
      necessary jar files used to realise subversion access.</p>
      
      <p>If you don't extend the above mentioned path declaration the only possibility to access
      a subversion repository is the so called <code>commandline</code> binding.</p>
      
      <p>In general you want to extend this path with additional libraries in order to use a
      specific binding to the subversion repository.</p>
  
      <p>The following list shows the requirements and the meaning of the available bindings
      (the order specifies the precedence):</p>
      
      <msubsubsection title="javahl">
      
        <p>This type of binding makes use of a Java native bridge in order to realise the subversion
        commands. These share libraries must be on your library path. You can launch the Ant
        script using the following option (of course you need to adjust the path):</p>
        
        <snippet>
          -Djava.library.path=${basedir}/javahl
        </snippet>
        
        <p>You also need to add the Jar equivalent of the binding which is typically named
        <code>svnjavahl.jar</code>.</p>
        
        <remark>If this binding doesn't seem to work, you should check whether the library 
        path is correct or not. You can use the <a href="http://ant.apache.org/manual/Tasks/echoproperties.html">echoproperties</a>
        to get this information.</remark>
        
      </msubsubsection>
      
      <msubsubsection title="svnkit">
        
        <p>The <a href="http://svnkit.com">svnkit</a> binding is purely java based. Using this
        binding requires the jar <code>svnkit.jar</code> to be used for the <i>svnant</i>
        declaration. You also need the <code>ganymed.jar</code> which provides the necessary
        functionality for SSH based communication.</p>
      
      </msubsubsection>

      <msubsubsection title="commandline">
      
        <p>This binding is the simpliest one and is considered to be a fallback solution. It
        just looks for the <i>svn</i> executable itself, so it must be locatable using the
        path specified within the propert <code>java.library.path</code>.</p>
        
      </msubsubsection>
  
    </msubsection>
  
  </msection>
  
  <msection id="changelog" title="Changelog">
  
    <snippet id="changelog" type="text">
      <xi:include parse="text" href="../changelog.txt"/>
    </snippet>
    
  </msection>
  
  <msection id="knownissues" title="Known issues">
  
    <p>This chapter provides some known issues which might be of interest when you're experiencing
    <i>weird</i> behaviour:</p>
    
    <msubsection title="General">
    
      <ul>
      
        <li><b>Mutable Ant properties</b><br/>
        <p>Basically Ant properties aren't supposed to be changed. This means that their value
        stays the same once they have been set. <i>svnant</i> doesn't take care of this so if
        you're <i>reusing</i> property names you should be aware that they can be overwritten.</p>
        <p>We won't change that behaviour since this is a historical result and modifying the
        behaviour might cause issues on current build scripts.</p> 
        </li>
        
      </ul>
      
    </msubsection>

    <msubsection title="JavaHL Binding">
    
      <ul>
        
        <li><code>propset</code> fails with binary code<br/>
        <p>If you're trying to use the <code>propset</code> command with the <code>file</code>
        attribute you might experience errors in case of binary data. This is an error within
        the JavaHL implementation and has been filed using the following issue:</p>
        <a href="http://subversion.tigris.org/issues/show_bug.cgi?id=3770">http://subversion.tigris.org/issues/show_bug.cgi?id=3770</a>
        </li>
        
      </ul>
    
    </msubsection>
    
  </msection>

  <msection id="authors" title="Authors">
  
    <ul>
      <li><a href="mailto:users@subclipse.tigris.org">C&#233;dric Chabanois</a></li>
    </ul>
  
  </msection>

</mdoc>